MARKO FREI

Senior Full Stack Developer

\ +48 61 625 55 98 @ markofrei94@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Experienced software developer proficient in many platforms and tools, focused on delivering business value through quality software. I am equally comfortable discussing requirements in the language of the business as I am in heads-down coding sprints. I can take hard problems from conception to production, designing the big picture and sweating the details. A lively debater around the planning table and a passionate, agile collaborator, I understand that the team succeeds together. I love creating distributed systems, prototyping with new technology, and automating the tedious. I have an intellectual curiosity fuels a fanatical devotion to skills improvement and constant learning.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Full Stack and Blockchain Engineer

02/2020 - 10/2022

Draglet

Munich, Germany

Full Time Remote Employer

- Created a system consist of swap, pool, staking, lending and borrowing contracts which improved the company income to 130%.
- Wrote smart contracts for NFT, Voting, Vesting. (https://kindkoalas.io, https://www.shreddedapes.io, https://kool.lol).
- Built and maintained strategic relationships with potential investors and business partners and brainstormed new ideas.
- Represented the company at various workshops and industry events and executed multiple key clerical tasks.
- Collaborated with colleagues from other departments and participated in the creation and testing of new software applications.

Senior Full Stack Developer

09/2018 - 12/2019

MyMeta

Toronto, Canada

Full Time Remote Employer

- Increased daily traffic from 45% to 80% by redesigning existing websites to improve user experience and incorporated SEO.
- Upgraded Angular 11 to Angular 14 and fixed some errors so that removed node module problem.
- Collaborated with 2 different development teams on 4 new project designs and feature improvements.
- Suggested 20+ improvements to product design and functionality as informed by userexperience reporting.
- Collaborated with 4 client service teams to understand and solve bottlenecks and proposed feature expansions by using Symfony.
- Architected, implemented, and maintained 5 performant and scalable data-processing back-end systems.

Front End Developer

10/2016 - 07/2018

Netdigix Systems

New Westminster, Canada

Full Time Employer

- Added an average of 25% increase in annual company revenue with an average of 15 clients per month.
- Designed 20+ front-end Web Interface for engineers and test-ops to control and monitor the onboard system.
- Analyzed and optimized performance bottlenecks in 8+ existing backend systems, such as database queries and storage solutions, to increase responsiveness.
- Led transition from Firebase to AWS, saving company \$3,700+ monthly and increasing load speeds by an average of 38%.
- Collaborated on Complexity Score tool, which removed process bottlenecks by assigning scores to cost, time, and compliance issues, increasing efficiency by 72%.
- Developed more than 10 cluster projects and utilized public cloud, computing infrastructure services using React and Redux.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science

Waseda University

09/2006 - 08/2010

Tokyo, Japan

Master of Computer Science

Douglas College

09/2014 - 08/2016 New Westminster, Canada

SKILLS

JavaScript · TypeScript · PHP · HTML5 ·

CSS3 · Python · Tailwind CSS · React.js ·

Vue.js · Angular · Node.js · Express.js ·

Laravel · Django · RestAPI · GraphQL ·

Redux · Solidity · Smart Contract ·

Ethereum

LANGUAGES

English Native

Chinese **Proficient**

STRENGTHS



Collaboration

Working in a team motivates me to give 100% every day. Collective intelligence is the most powerful tool for companies.

Q Attention to Detail

Always concentrate on details because even an unimportant error could ruin the code.

Prioritizing الر

Prioritizing is why I use 100% of my energy and mental capacity for the most complex and thought-provoking tasks.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer

01/2011 - 08/2014

Facility Team

Tokyo, Japan

Full Time Employer

- Transitioned an existing Backbone.js application to React.
- Redesigned, simplified, and implemented a new version of an existing alerting application
 that contained over 100 form fields and reduced the amount of customer support calls
 with the simplified redesign.
- Developed a universal search feature for a customer-facing analytics application that allowed all the application's data entities to the searched within a single interface.
- Implemented various private APIs on a Node.js and PostgreSQL back end.
- Enhanced user experience and accomplish webpage objectives by creating site structure, navigation, page optimization and graphics integration.
- Created a Mobile Responsive User Experience with CSS Flex box that allowed crossplatform accessibility to the website on any device with primary use on mobile. This increased the number of 5 star User Experience/User Interface reviews by 360%.